# Elijah Silverman

New York City | 551-246-4271 | <u>elijahmsilverman@gmail.com</u> <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>Website</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u>

#### **FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Full Stack Developer experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript-based programming with a focus on React.js. With a background in Business Administration and Consulting, I bring an understanding of the macro environment and the importance of collaboration and innovation. o

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React.js, Python, REST, CSS, HTML

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Treadlite - GitHub | Demo

Carbon-footprint calculator with a social element. (React/Ruby)

- Created a self-referential model for users to easily create and destroy 'follows'
- Utilized Rails Auth, bcrypt, React, validations, and Cookies to build secure signup/login
- Built a comprehensive calculation based on government data which takes in 13 user inputs to generate a 'score'
- · Leveraged Material UI to build a functional and complex, yet beautiful and mobile-friendly user interface

# Stuck-in-space - GitHub | Demo

RPG that imitates classic CLI-style games. (React/Ruby)

- Generated complex back-end models to enable cascading effects based on gameplay
- Styled the front-end of the game to accurately resemble an 80's style terminal using CSS, Semantic UI, and Typewriter
- Crafted a tool that accepts over a dozen multi-word user commands and deciphers actions from items, and menu calls

## Snap-note - GitHub | Demo

Note-taking tool that categorizes notes based on a user's calendar and when the note was created. (React/Ruby)

- Implemented rich text editor with WYSIWYG, enabling edits and updates to persist in full
- Worked with PostgreSQL, implementing all CRUD methods through ActiveRecord, and Ruby on Rails
- Programmed a date comparison method using Luxon and Ruby to determine if note submission was part of an event

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **YYA Consulting & Management**

Consultant

Tel-Aviv, Israel 11/2020 - 08/2021

- Coordinated with a Big-4 global consulting firm on multiple projects, facilitating their business development, resulting in increased follow-up contracts
- Designed engaging, informative, and dynamic client-facing deliverables alongside teams of 4-7 consultants and field experts, improving the rate of re-signing
- Interpreted data-heavy research trends for the Air Force Research Laboratory, informing their investment strategy
- Developed client proposals for customers in Mobility, Smart City Management, UAV, IT, and Real Estate in three different continents, while reducing the firm's turnaround time and increasing contracts
- Managed onboarding of new employees. New hires reported to me for the first two months of employment

Dindex

Tel-Aviv, Israel

**Business Development Intern** 

11/2018 - 01/2019

 Leveraged LinkedIn network and desktop research to target, and contact relevant venture capital firms to secure financing, leading to a substantial increase in meetings

## **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** 

New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

10/2021 - 01/2022

# **IDC Herzliya (Reichman University)**

Tel-Aviv, Israel

Bachelor of Arts (BA), Business Administration and Entrepreneurship.

2021

- GPA 4.0, Magna Cum Laude, Dean's List Distinction